[Music]
foreign
in today's video we're going to be
issuing a mathematical challenge for the
Hebrew Israelites now in order to
understand this mathematical challenge
this math problem we need to understand
the basic belief of the Hebrew
Israelites and that is this
Hebrew Israelites believe that the 400
year period of the transatlantic slave
trade proves the Hebrew Israelite to be
the true people of God
they believe that this is pointed to in
Bible prophecy and foretold in the
curses spoken of in Deuteronomy 28. so
in order to break down this this uh this
belief in order to to understand the
mathematical challenge that will be
presented in this video the first thing
we're going to need to do is to go to
this 400 year period and I'm going to
show you the four mathematic problems
that I will be presenting in this video
now you're looking at these equations
and you're going what in the world is
that 400 does not equal C 70 does not
equal 400 400 does not equal 800 and
1260 equals x what is that about you
will find out just follow along and
follow carefully
let's go to this 400 year this mention
of the 400 year Prophecy in the Bible it
is mentioned about four or five times in
the scriptures either using the 400 or
430 year period so we're not going to
get into the difference between the 400
and 430 that's not the purpose of this
presentation we're simply going to say
this is estimated to be 400 years of
captivity that is being spoken of here
the four or five places that are
mentioned in the Bible and we're not
going to look at all of those we're just
going to look at two one in Genesis and
one in the book of Acts so let's read
the Genesis 15 verse 13 and 14 account
and here God is speaking to Abram and it
says he said unto Abram no for surety
that thy seed shall be a stranger in a
land that is not theirs and Shall Serve
them and they shall afflict them 400
years
verse 14.
and also that Nation to whom they Shall
Serve will I judge and afterward shall
they come out with great substance so
here we have the first mention of this
400 year prophecy and this 400 year
prophecy as we see in the text is
pointing to Abraham's seed going into
captivity for 400 years something we
know happened during the the time of
Egypt now let's look at the second place
that it is mentioned and it is in the
book of Acts chapter 7 verse 6 which is
simply referring back to Genesis notice
what it says and God spake on this wise
that his seed should sojourn in a
Strange Land and that they should bring
them into bondage and then treat them
evil for 400 years so I want you to
notice here that the children of Israel
uh are in bondage for 400 years
we know that in the book of Exodus Moses
comes to deliver them out of that 400
year period of captivity and then we
have Moses leading the children of
Israel through the Wilderness so that's
Exodus uh Leviticus numbers and then we
get to the book of Deuteronomy where the
curses are found
Deuteronomy 28 15 we read but it shall
come to pass if thou will not hearken
unto the voice of the Lord thy God to
observe to do all his Commandments and
his statutes which I command thee this
day that all these curses shall come
upon thee and overtake thee and beloved
this brings us to our first equation now
please watch this
notice the sequence in Genesis you have
the prophecy being given to Abraham you
have that prophecy being fulfilled 400
years between the Book of Genesis and in
the beginning of the book of Exodus
Moses comes on the scene to the liver
and then you have Deuteronomy 28 where
the curses are found and the curses are
referring to what will happen to the
children of Israel if they disobey in
the future
why is this significant
here is why challenge number one
is that the 400 years were not connected
to the curses in Deuteronomy 28.
let me say it again
the 400 years
of bondage that the children of Israel
faced
in Egypt had nothing to do with the
curses of Deuteronomy 28 they were not
connected the reason that the children
of Israel spent 400 years in captivity
was not because of curses
the curses came after they came out of
captivity when we hear Hebrew Israelites
saying that there was a prophecy that
the children of Israel the Israelites
would spend 400 years in captivity
sometime in the future in America
you cannot use
the prophecy being given in Genesis
to point to that
so that's math challenge number one
you've taken the 400 years that number
and connected it made it equal to
something that it is not it is not equal
to the curses
problem number two
problem number two is that 70 does not
equal
400. what do you mean by this pastor
follow along
the Bible says in Jeremiah 25 11
and before I read that let me let me
mention this
the curse is given in Deuteronomy 28
did not Point backward
to their Egyptian captivity it pointed
forward to Babylonian captivity and
there was a time period given in
connection with the Babylonian captivity
and that was 70 years not 400 years 70
years notice Jeremiah 25 and verse 11
and this whole land shall be a
desolation and an astonishment and these
nations Shall Serve the king of Babylon
70 years again
in Jeremiah 29 verse 10 the Bible says
for thus say the Lord that after 70
years be accomplished at Babylon I will
visit you and perform my good word
toward you in causing you to return to
this place so again we see that the
curses were pointing forward to a
70-year period not a 400 year period in
fact the Prophet Daniel
who is living at the end of this 70-year
period writes this in Daniel 9 verse 2.
he says in the first year of his Reign I
Daniel understood my books the number of
the years whereof the word of the Lord
came to Jeremiah the prophet that he
would accomplish how long 70 years in
the desolations of Jerusalem Daniel then
begins to pray and in his prayer he's
confessing the sins of these people and
notice what he says in verse 11. yea all
Israel have transgressed thy law even by
departing that they might not obey thy
voice
therefore the curse the curse is poured
upon us and the oath that is written in
the law of Moses the servant of God
because we have sinned against him so I
want you to see here that Daniel is
clearly linking the children of Israel's
captivity in Babylon that to the curses
of Deuteronomy 28.
he is linking this 70-year period to the
curses found in Deuteronomy 28 the 70
does not equal 400.
now let me demonstrate to you just how
accurately
all of Deuteronomy 28 was fulfilled in
the Babylonian captivity so there's a
whole lot of curses but I'm just going
to focus on several for the sake of time
in Deuteronomy 28 15 here's what it says
but if so if it shall come to pass if
you not hearken unto the voice of the
Lord your God to observe to do all his
Commandments which he commands this day
that all these curses shall come upon
thee and overtake thee and then the
curses begin to be listed
notice with me verse 36.
the Lord shall bring thee and thy King
which Thou shalt set over thee unto a
nation which neither thou nor thy
fathers have known and there shalt thou
serve other gods wood and stone was this
fulfilled in the Babylonian captivity
knows with me second Kings chapter 24
verse 15 where the Bible says and he
carried away jehoican to Babylon and the
King's mother and the Kings wise and his
officers and the mighty of the land
those carried he into captivity from
Jerusalem to Babylon what about
Deuteronomy 28 verse 41 Thou shalt
begets sons and daughters but thou shall
not enjoy them for they shall go into
captivity was this fulfilled in the
reign of Babylon the answer is yes
notice Lamentations chapter 1 verse 5
her adversaries are the chief her
enemies Prosper for the Lord has
Afflicted her for the multitude of her
transgressions her children are gone
into captivity be before the enemy it is
clear here that this was fulfilled
during the Babylonian captivity what
about Deuteronomy 28 and verse 48
the Bible says here therefore Thou shalt
serve thine enemies which the Lord shall
send against thee in a hunger and in
thirst and in nakedness and in want of
all things and he shall put a yoke of
iron upon thy neck until he have
destroyed thee was this fulfilled notice
Jeremiah 28 14 for thus saith the Lord
of hosts the god of Israel I have put a
yoke of iron upon the neck of all these
nations that they may serve
Nebuchadnezzar King of Babylon and they
shall serve him and I have given him the
Beast of the field also you can see
beloved that this is all being fulfilled
in the Captivity of Babylon in
Deuteronomy 28 verse 49 another curse
the Lord shall bring a nation against
thee from far from the end of the Earth
as Swift as the eagle flyeth a nation
whose tongue thou shall not understand
now was this fulfilled during the
Babylonian captivity watch this
in the Book of Daniel chapter 7 four
beasts are described these beasts
represent Nations and the Nations that
are being described in Daniel chapter 7
are Babylon meet a person Greece Rome
the First Nation Babylon notice how it's
described Daniel 7 3 and 4 and four
great beasts came up from the sea
diverse one from another the first that
would be Babylon was like a lion and had
what kind of wings
Eagles wings
Eagles Wings beloved this very curse is
being fulfilled in the reign of Babylon
notice Deuteronomy 28 verse 50 a nation
of fierce countenance which shall not
regard the person of all nor so favored
to the young was this fulfilled second
chronicles 36 17 therefore he brought
upon them the king of the chaldees who
slew their young men with the sword in
the house of the sanctuary and had no
compassion on the young man or Maiden
old man or him that stooped for age he
gave them all into his hand
what about Deuteronomy 28 52 here it
says he shall besiege thee and all thy
Gates until thy high and fence walls
come down we're in thou trusted
throughout all thy land and he shall
besiege thee in all thy Gates throughout
all thy land was this fulfilled during
the Babylonian captivity Second Kings 24
verse 10 and 11 read this
at the time the Servants of
Nebuchadnezzar King of Babylon came up
against Jerusalem and the city was
besieged and Nebuchadnezzar King of
Babylon came against the city and his
servants did besiege it beloved this is
absolutely clear I'm going to show you
one more verse Deuteronomy 28 verse 68
the final curse it says the Lord shall
bring thee into Egypt again with ships
by the way whereof I spake unto thee
Thou shalt see it no more again
and there you shall be sold unto your
enemies for Bond men and bond women and
no man shall buy you now please note the
text does not say and the Lord shall
bring thee into America
no it says the Lord shall bring thee
into Egypt
was this fulfilled all we need to do
beloved is go to Jeremiah chapter 44 and
verse 12 where God is war is is is
giving a warning about the people who
were left after Babylon besieges the
city notice what it says
and I will take the remnant of Judah
those left after the siege that have set
their faces to go into the land of Egypt
to sojourn there and they shall all be
consumed and fall in the land of Egypt
they shall even be consumed by The Sword
and by famine they shall die from the
least even unto the greatest By The
Sword and by famine and they shall be an
execration and an astonishment and a
curse and a reproach it is clear that
the 70 week or the 70 years is what is
connected with the curse is not 400
years
this brings us to our third challenge
which is simply this 400 does not equal
800. okay pastor what does that mean
God gave one 400 year prophecy he did
not say the children of Israel will go
into captivity for 400 years and then
again another 400 years later if he
meant that he would have said 800 years
there is not another a second 400 year
Prophecy in the Bible the only 400 year
Prophecy in the Bible is the one where
the children of Israel have gone into
Egypt
that is it not America
the 400 cannot be made to equal 800
meaning 400 in the book of Exodus and
then 400 for the transatlantic slave
trade that's 800. that's not 400.
if God
God said 800 he would have said 400 at
this time and then 400 at that time
he doesn't do that
so how do you take 400 years and Tack on
another 400 to it
it does not work the math does not work
and since there's only one 400 year
prophecy then what needs to happen is
you need to show your work of how this
400 years
is all of a sudden
extended into the future
when remember the 400 years had nothing
to do with the original curses in
Deuteronomy 28 because those curses came
after the 400 years
so now that we see these challenges
we're prepared to look at our final
challenge this is the challenge
of 1
260 equals X
so what is this challenge about
come with me to the Book of Revelation
chapter 12 and I want you to notice with
me beginning with verse one the Bible
says they were prayer they're repaired a
great Wonder in heaven a woman clothed
with the sun and the moon under her feet
and upon her head a crown of 12 stars
and she being with child cried
travailing in birth and pain to be
delivered now let me just make this very
simple this woman is symbolic of God's
people it is symbolic of Israel but this
is Old Testament Israel why because the
child which is Jesus has not been born
yet
so this prophecy is showing describing
Israel waiting for the birth of the
Messiah
reading on in verse 3 the Bible says and
there appeared another Wonder in heaven
and behold a great red dragon having
seven heads and ten horns and seven
crowns upon his heads and his tail drew
the third part of the stars of heaven
and did cast him to the earth and the
dragon this is what I want you to focus
on the dragon stood before the woman
which was ready to be delivered for to
devour her child as soon as it was born
so now we see this this conflict where
whatever power this is which we're not
even going to focus on right now is is
described as trying to destroy Jesus
we go to verse 5 and here is what I want
you to see the Bible says and she
brought forth a man-child who was to
rule all nations with a rod of iron
and her child was caught up unto God and
to his throne so in this one verse we
now have the birth death burial
resurrection and Ascension of Jesus into
heaven
so whatever we're about to read next
occurs after the cross
so I want you to know verse 6 and verse
14.
the Bible says here and the woman so who
is the woman it is Israel it is Israel
now in the New Testament right now after
the Old Testament so this is the woman
presently the woman represents Israel
after the cross the Bible says the woman
fled Into the Wilderness where she has a
place prepared of God that they should
feed her there one thousand two hundred
and three score days verse 14 is going
to tell us the same thing and to the
woman we're given two wings of a great
Eagle that she might fly into the
Wilderness into her place where she is
nourished
for a time and times and half a time
from the face of the serpent let me just
read one more verse verse 15 and 16 and
the serpent casts out of his mouth water
as a flood after the woman that he might
cause her to be carried away of the
flood and the Earth helped the woman and
the Earth opened her mouth and swallowed
up the flood which the Dragon cast out
of his mouth now what is this final
mathematical problem well here it is
if we want to know the identity of
Israel
all we need to do
is identify or connect this 1260
time period mathematical step to Israel
so for the Hebrew Israelite what that
means is you have to demonstrate how
this
1260 day time period time times that I
have uh 1203 score days how does that
connect with your movement
please note this numbers don't lie
so this means that you would have to
provide beginning dates and ending date
to show exactly this time period and how
your movement is connected to it
you can't just make something up the the
math has to fit
so so imagine as it were that this is a
time stamp that helps us identify who
the true Israel of God is it's kind of
like if a crime happened and you have an
alibi because I was here at this time
okay you know then that person is off
the hook because they were there this
the woman has a time stamp it's a
mathematical equation and
whoever the true woman is will be able
to verify to identify the events of this
time period and her connection with it
so again
you would have to demonstrate
beginning year
ending year beginning date ending date I
need you to see this
true Hebrew Israelites
are not connected with the 400 years of
Genesis 15 they are connected with the
1260 prophetic days of Revelation
chapter 12.
that's the number we're to be looking
for not 400 1260.
by the way
during this 1260 this woman is evidently
blessed and not cursed
let me say it again she is being
protected by God not cursed
so what I need you to understand is that
the 400 years that was in the past and
that wasn't even connected to the curses
it's the 70 years that we're connected
to the curses and that is passed too in
the New Testament in the Book of
Revelation the end time Israel of God is
connected not with 400 not with 70 but
with 1260.
so now you have to demonstrate how your
movement is identified how was your
movement in the wilderness
how was your movement in the wilderness
for for this 1260 uh prophetic period
explain that what's the wilderness
how did the Earth open up her mouth and
swallow up the flood to preserve this
movement and again this movement is not
under a curse yes they're being
persecuted but they're not under a curse
so how are we taking
the 400 years which apply to something
totally different
and making it applicable to the
transatlantic slave trade
and then using that to identify see we
are Israel
there's your math problem
there are your four mathematical
challenges number one
400 the 400 years was not connected with
the curses
number two
the 70 years does not equal 400 the
curses were fulfilled in the 70-year
prophecy not the 400 years which
happened before it number three
400 does not equal 800. how are we
taking the 400 years attributed to Egypt
and apply and applying a second 400
years to the transatlantic slave trade
and number four
1260 equals what
show us the beginning date and the
ending date of your 1260 and how your
movement fulfilled this prophecy how was
your movement in the wilderness
not in Egypt in the wilderness that's
where it says the movie was in the
wilderness how was your movement in the
wilderness what is the Wilderness how
long is this 1260 beginning date ending
date there's a mathematical problem
so
it is my prayer that as you're
attempting to solve these mathematical
challenges
and you discover that they cannot be
solved
that you discover that it actually is a
mathematical problem that reveals error
of belief
it is my prayer that you will be willing
to follow truth no matter where it leads
may God bless you
in your math work oh by the way show
your work
you know in math class when they say
you're trying to solve a problem show
your work
show your work show us 1260 show us how
you get 400 out of 800 out of 400 show
us how 70 equals 400 show us how 400
equals to the curses
God bless you
in your search for truth
amen
[Music]